Thank you.
That you'll consider, you'll feel it, you'll ponder what the Lord has been saying to you through the psalm, through the teaching, through the Scripture that we read.
Canaanite has at least six different words that are intimately connected with it.
If you can pick those up on the slide here.
So the first is contemplation.
Jesus said, do this in remembrance of me.
We remember what he's done.
We take time to remember.
Examination.
Paul tells us to examine ourselves before we partake,
or we might not partake in unworthy manner.
Repentance.
Now, by the way, I think this is probably one of the most beautiful words in the entire Scriptures.
This morning, I can start from.
No matter what I have done in the community,
what I've done five minutes for them,
I can turn five.
It's a gift.
What a wonderful word.
Repentance.
I mean for goodness, what comes out of repentance,
that we are forgiven.
Unity.
The word communion literally means common union.
The Greek word is koinimia.
We'll talk more about it.
It's translated communion.
It's also translated fellowship.
That communion is an act of our oneness.
We do it collectively because we have been made one in him.
And then last of all, probably the word that is most common to communion worldwide.
Euthers.
Euthers means good.
Euthers means grace.
The good grace, which is translated thanksgiving.
Given what he has done.
That's definitely not different.
And so this morning, we're going to walk through each one of these words,
one by one.
We just finished a series about spiritual stations,
ways that we're treating to God.
So if we think about the kingdom and the spiritual stations,
communion is a song that every station plays.
Times of heart, times of heart, times of head, times of mystery, times of service.
This morning also, we will partake closely in a way
that will rip away the domestication of this spiritual practice
from a collective, whitewashed view of the club.
You know, the youth are going to watch the commission.
I know people who force themselves to watch it every year.
It's traumatizing.
And with that, it's the person.
Why is it watching the cause?
The point for our film is so traumatizing.
Why is this thing in our life not equally traumatizing?
That we would rip away our domestication of what Jesus has done
and understand the extent of what he truly paid.
Because only then can we really appreciate the resurrection.
The first word that we're going to focus on is
Elah, I'm sorry, contemplation.
And this will be my longest teaching this morning.
It will be short blocks of teaching.
Do this in remembrance of me.
You know, in the Bible, the word remember is a rather pregnant word.
It's not just, you know, cognitively acknowledged.
But remember flows through the Scriptures
in sometimes speaking about God,
that God says, I will remember.
And other times calling us to remember.
It is this thinking of remember that God remembers you.
Anyone else like me where eventually you get to a place
where you just cry out like the psalmist,
how long, oh Lord, will you forget me?
How long will I struggle with this thing
saying over and over and over again, Lord?
How long do I have to fit in the midst of my circumstance?
Genesis 6, Genesis 6, verse 17.
It tells us that after God had blood of the world
to wipe away evil in the world in that current context.
But you know, he's got a rainbow on this cloud.
And it says, whenever the rainbow appears in the clouds,
God said, I will see it.
And remember the everlasting covenant
between God and all the living creatures of the earth.
God does this so that he remembers.
Not that he needs to remember.
No, we need to remember that he remembers.
We need to remember that he does not forget.
And so when you're on a spot of saying,
God, how long will you forget your word?
And he needs an invitation to remember
if he remembers me.
Give it in remembrance of me.
Exodus 20, verse 8.
Remember the Sabbath.
Again, it's not just a kind of thing,
but remember it in such a way that you live
in accordance with this wonderful gift
that God gave his people of rest.
In Deuteronomy, when they instituted the crossover,
really the initiation of what became
the celebration of communion.
Because it was a Passover meal
that Jesus reimagined as a new Christian at Passover.
In that context, the bread, the unleavened bread,
is called the bread of a friction
to remember their departure from closure.
And so as we're talking to communion,
it's a remembrance of our departure
from closure to sin.
You are no longer owned by the evil one.
You're no longer owned by your flesh.
Those whom the Lord has set free are
free indeed.
Joshua sets up rock piles
every time God does something amazing
so that they might remember what God has done.
And my favorite story of setting up rock piles
is when they crossed through the Jordan
and they set up two piles of rocks.
One on the shore.
They took rocks out of the middle of the river
and they, you know, God flipped the river.
They walked across their Thomas land.
They set up, they set up a set of rock piles
so that they could tell their kids
that they could remember what God had done.
And then, do you remember where they set
a second pile of rock in the middle of the river?
Why would you set up something to remember
in a place that no one can see?
Or here's the answer.
You cannot feel it
until there's such a grasp
that the water has gone so low.
When you're in that place of crying out,
Lord, how long will you forget me?
It doesn't rain.
We're an agricultural society.
We need to eat.
And the water gets so low
and the rock's gone off.
It's sin.
And you remember.
You remember.
The thief on the cross, remember me.
He didn't just say, hey, you know,
don't forget my name.
But remember me when you move into paradise.
You know, sometimes I feel like
we are the island of misfit toys
and Rudolph the world knows reindeer.
Remember that island?
Nobody wants to curl in the box.
Their real anguish
was after meeting Rudolph
and meeting this elf
that wants to become a, what, a dentist.
That's right.
He wants to become a dentist.
And they promised that they will tell Santa
because every year,
Santa doesn't stop the pigs.
He wants to take them up
to take them to where the boys and girls are,
which was a whole life purpose.
And so they sit there
and they wait
and they gather
and finally one of them says,
that's what I'm going to say.
Jesus, I've got these things.
You know, sometimes there are storms
in our life
that create context.
They want to be deep in our faith
if in those moments
we will remember the rock bar
that was submerged
and is now thrown up.
If we remember that
wonderful Christmas story
how joyful they were
when they finally saw the red
boop, boop, boop.
If we don't.
Remember.
Communion is an act
of remembering.
Can we take 30 seconds
for some of you
to just
remember what you've done?
to just be able to see.
Thank you.
I'm going to take 30 seconds
and I'm going to take 30 seconds
examination
Paul says a man ought to examine himself
before he eats of the bread
and drinks of the cup
you know John Wesley
in the midst of the revivals that he led
would require that all of his itinerary preachers
they'd come to more churches
than they had pastors for him
they were just all over the frontier
and so they would ride from church to church
to church to church to church
to preach the gospel
and to do communion
and to counsel with people
and he had very little requirements of them
but one of the things he required that they do
one of the things that they say
is that the Methodists were there
while the Presbyterians were still training
their people back in the city
they just went
but one of the things that was critical
was every itinerant preacher
every night at the end of the day
would do a terrible examen
they would sit down at the end of the day
and they would ask themselves two questions
where did I encounter God today
that I can give him some examen
and the second question
where were you going to have
moving or speaking
is he not speaking
now if you're a mature Christian
I would actually encourage you to do this
on a daily basis
so as I say mature
it's actually a hard discipline to do
you know you just start on your day
and squirrel
it's just a hard
it's a living
but if you're able
to take those times
through contemplates
but in the private zoning
it's important to remember
that it's not the condemnation
Paul said
there is now therefore
no condemnation
there's no condemnation
but the ditch
on the other side
of that piece
the one ditch
is that we condemn ourselves
we condemn ourselves
the other ditch
is that we never examined
we say go on
forgive him
I'm good to go
and no no no
if you read that message
it goes on to say
that those who live
in accordance with the Spirit
have set their mind
on what the Spirit
design is
so this act
of examination
is to set our mind
on what the Spirit
design is
what is God
saying to you
how is your light
mixed up
with the revealed
word of God
that you're aware of
so
my kids all knew
that there were
multiple levels
of pain
we would require
that they clean
their room daily
and if you would have
come to my house
you would probably
would have looked at me
and said that's not clean
we had a second level
of clean
that we called
just clean
and just clean
was always
oh
every day
yes
just clean
but we had a third
level of clean
my mother
I wasn't allowed
to eat anything
myself
until I was like four
and she received me
because she didn't want
me throwing anything
in any way
exact opposite
by the way
of the way my wife
raised our son
he was like
a year and a half
eating spaghetti
on his own
you know
I would get up and go
okay my grouse
out level's done
I gotta go home
but my mom
it had to be
until you could do it
properly
you couldn't do it yourself
and so
with our kids
we had these
we had this clean
and then we had
manicure
an opportunity
to do a manicure
in a situation
hopefully we examine
all the time
because
it's a terrible thing
and examine
not with condemnation
for Israel though
for no condemnation
it was a sincere
desire
to set our mind
on what
the spirit
is done with
we're going to worship the Lord
to find speed in your love
it's probably starting to
find a speed in your love
so stand before the Lord
is made
when that's done
we're going to have
it's the quiet music
for you to actually examine
and from this point on
in the service
I'm not going to stand
or sit
but you get the posture
that helps you
to connect with God
the most
so when you examine
if you want to continue
to stand
feel free
if you want to stick
to examine
feel free
stand in your life
you wish to stand
just get out of here
and then all
you still can
but God's sons is dead
thank you all
for being here this morning
is the only one
that's going to be
church is required
of repentance
for the same thing
let that rock pile
of what God has done
that appears in the midst
of a river
that is running dry
remind me
he has not forgotten you
he's not forgotten you
he died to be
in relationship with you
and to pour out
not just with blood
but to pour out
his love
spread it abroad
in our hearts
so let us repent
as we approach
the table today
I encourage you
to be reminded
of the past
as soon
so that you might
be reminded
of the extent
of his forgiveness
for you
we're going to
partake of communion
at the table
but as you can
this row
of the middle
or this row
will come
and will approach
the table
from the side
of the bed
and move out
around the back
to come back in
we're going to
partake through
intention
so Jesus' body
was broken
for us
and Jesus chose
for his body
to be broken
some say
the Romans
broke him
and Scriptures
tell us
that God
did this
this is God
but it's also
true that
our sin
has broken
him
and so today
I'm going to
invite you
as you partake
to actually
break off
a piece of
grace
recognizing
your sin
but as you
get
remember that
it is for
the remission
of sin
that when
you claim
he is faithful
and just
he forgives us
our sins
and he cleanses
us from
all unrighteousness
how much
unrighteousness
all unrighteousness
Father we thank you
for these elements
Lord we pray
that you would
bless them
and bless
our heart
and minds
we do this
because you
have ordered
it
you have
to follow
them
to do it
as often
as you can
in remembrance
of what you
have done
and so Lord
Jesus meet
with your people
at the table
as each one
comes and
breaks off
bread
and then
dips the bread
into the cup
and receives
in your name
meet yourself
in my prayer
in the strong
name of Jesus
Amen
but just
on your mind
as you can
breaks again
get the things
of the cup
and your shoes
if you prefer
there is
unroving bread
that you can take
there is also
a soft-contained
biscuit
that you may take
but let's
approach the table
and as you are
ready
the table is open
the gate is wide
Thank you.
And it's all about you.
It's all about you.
I'm sorry, Lord.
And it's all about you.
It's all about you.
I'm sorry, Lord.
If I know this world, though I'm so desperate, I've got to use this world.
Whatever you can't afford, hold on to this world, let me still go for another world.
And I'll bring you more than I can't afford, for this long time, it's not what you have to cry.
Research must be further than you, through the ways we track you, the world has given you to my heart.
I'm coming back to the heart of the world, and it's all about you, it's all about you, Jesus.
I'm sorry, Lord, for the pain of the pain, it's all about you, it's all about you, Jesus.
I'm coming back to the heart of the world, and it's all about you, Jesus.
And it's all about you, Jesus.
I'm coming back to the heart of the world, and it's all about you.
I'm coming back to the heart of the world, and it's all about you, Jesus.
I'm coming back to the heart of the world, and I'm coming back to the heart of the world, and it's all about you, Jesus.
This is my blood of the covenant, which was poured out for the name for the forgiveness of sins.
We're convinced that the Christian priesthood, we are a priesthood of believers.
We have the privilege of going directly to God.
We also have the privilege of taking one another to God and representing God to one another as a priesthood of his kingdom.
And so based on your faith in Jesus, and the truth of God's word, inasmuch as your confession was fulfilled, I proclaim that your sins are forgiven.
I'm saying that your sins are forgiven.